### Contact

03333468440 (Mobile) ahsn\_zmeer@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ahsanzameer-16558a22 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

PHP

Laravel

WordPress

### Languages

Urdu

English

#### Honors-Awards

Employee of the year award

# Ahsan Zameer

Software Team Lead | PHP | Laravel | CodeIgniter | Wordpress Pakistan

### Summary

I am a devoted and ambitious professional developer with more than 10 years of extensive developing experience that comes from working with numerous key clients & dealing with freelance projects.

With extensive knowledge of PHP and other programming languages I make the web applications talk.

### Experience

Marcel Tech Pvt Ltd Software Development Team Lead June 2021 - Present (1 year 7 months) Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan

Smart Web Agency Development Team Lead September 2019 - December 2020 (1 year 4 months) Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan

Batoota Pvt Ltd Project Consultant August 2019 - April 2020 (9 months) Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan

#### **Afiniti**

1 year 10 months

Senior Software Engineer
February 2019 - August 2019 (7 months)

Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan

Software Engineer November 2017 - January 2019 (1 year 3 months) Karachi PcsInternational
Senior PHP Developer
December 2012 - October 2017 (4 years 11 months)
Karachi

- Acting as a Team Lead and guiding junior developers
- Create mockups and wireframes for new projects.
- Create & develop websites on Codeigniter and Wordpress
- · Maneuvering with custom PHP code
- · Working on ERPs and looking after quality assurance
- Working with Google, Twitter, Facebook & Other APIs
- · Reporting on development issues and subsequent progress

### **AMGLOBALS**

Software Engg.

August 2012 - November 2012 (4 months)

Karachi

- Create & develop websites on Wordpress, Codelgniter & Joomla
- Developing shopping carts using Wordpress & OpenCart

Xtreme Solutions Software Engineer January 2012 - July 2012 (7 months) Karachi

- Create & develop websites on Wordpress & Joomla
- · Developing shopping carts using Wordpress & Joomla

Source Code Tech Team Lead Project OAK November 2010 - December 2011 (1 year 2 months) Karachi

- Acting as a Team Lead
- Create & develop websites using Wordpress
- Taking care of On and Off page Search Engine Optimization
- Strategizing development projects and business models

## Education

**PAF-KIET** 

Master's Degree, MCS · (2015 - 2017)

University Of Karachi Bachelor's Degree, B.com · (2007 - 2009)

Crescent Bahria Cadet College matriculation, English, Mathematics, Physics · (2002 - 2004)